but you guys can never guess what that
floppy disk is for what's up traders my
name is hunter this is hunter FX this
channel is so goddamn alpha so woke so
elites then I'm gonna teach you guys
stuff that I don't even know how to do
[Music]
that's right let me just first say that
trading the news is very very risky and
I am by no means an expert in it and you
could do this maybe in a fundamental
terms but again I don't trade
fundamentals I think trading the news is
somewhat just gambling to me but I do
know people that do trade these
strategies on the NFP with very high
success rate so these are basically
strategies that I've heard from friends
that are actually able to do it and I'm
basically going to tell you how to do
them and I've tried myself I've had some
success it hasn't worked out very well
for me in the past that being said
you're very much welcome to try these
out for your own I know NFP is tomorrow
or you could try them out every single
week just make sure that you're really
testing them out and going with a low
bet size when you're first trying out
because like we know news is extruding
volatile make sure you got your stops
make sure you got your profits and you
got to react very quickly all right
first of all guys we're gonna be looking
at the euro USD for these examples you
can also look at any USD pair the best
ones on NFP are euro USD and USD cad USD
cad is usually got the craziest
volatility because there's a couple
different releases at the same time for
both the USD and for the cad pair but
then you can also look at any of their
USD pair some people like to trade the
yen it's usually pretty obvious with
what's going to happen on the yen as
well so guys what we're gonna be doing
for this first strategy it's essentially
a breakout trading strategy and you're
gonna be looking for a very very quick
scalp and what you're gonna be doing is
you're gonna be jumping down to this
one minute here and you're gonna draw
the range highs and lows and because we
don't actually know what direction is
gonna be going unless you have some
fundamental bias that you actually want
to follow that's not what we're doing
here in this video what we're doing here
in this video is simply looking at the
previous highs and lows on this one
minute time frame because that's where
it's really gonna matter and then you're
gonna be looking for the breakout of
those most recent highs and lows and
then you're gonna shoot for a roughly 10
hip profit and that's it you're gonna be
looking at a previous area that most
likely is going to act as some sort of
support or resistance so you can see
right around here that's actually a
decent area if we look 10 pips in the
other direction after a breakout out of
that range you can see right here that
would be a great place for the market
makers to spike down to and stop hunt
and then reverse so it's gonna be very
important for every single strategy you
do things very quickly essentially
because a lot of this is going to be
stop hunts so what we do is we place a
buy stop here and a sell stop here so
that means when it breaks below that
price it'll instantly buy it up and
enter the position for a sell if it goes
to the downside and for a buy if it goes
to the upside and then what you're gonna
need to do is you're gonna essentially
be taking your profit instantly as well
because it's just gonna shoot straight
down you're gonna take your profit
immediately at that level and then
you're gonna take your profit
immediately at that level that's the
first strategy the second strategy here
guys this is one that my friend does use
he's crazy I don't know how he does it
he does it so damn quickly and he's got
like an 80% success rate on this and
it's actually quite unbelievable I never
had the best success rate with it maybe
I'm not fast enough maybe I'm not doing
it perfectly properly but this is how he
does it and essentially we're gonna be
looking for that
major move and then move back very
quickly so that obvious fake out that I
was just telling you that you know maybe
this level was gonna be a fake out so
very often on NFP what's going to happen
is it's gonna fake in one direction
catch out these breakout buyers right
that's why I said in that first strategy
you're taking your product and pretty
much instantly because you want to get
out before the fake out begins so
they're gonna fake you out in one
direction so let's look if it for
example went to the downside and it
faked us out here maybe there was
breakout buyers on this level too and it
would go just goes slightly below and
then it would come right back up so
essentially what we're gonna be looking
for is a 10 pip move into a direction so
right around there a 10 pip move we're
gonna look for that breakout fake out
we're gonna take the reversal very
quickly you're gonna have to leave a
resting order there behind some sort of
level and then it's gonna rally back in
the other direction and we're looking
for a 10 to 15 pip move back in the
other direction so you'll see that it'll
come back very quickly and sometimes
it'll actually go even farther but we
don't want to be greedy here we want to
be very very quick essentially this is a
strategy that you're going to be taking
very very small gains and your losses
are gonna be less likely because you're
gonna have mostly winners but your
losses will of course be bigger this is
something that you're gonna have to take
into account because you're gonna have
maybe an 80% success rate but you need
to know when to cut your trades wrong
very quickly and I would say if they're
going about double the length of what
you were planning as a take profit then
you want to cut that trade off
immediately so in the other direction
here guys if it had actually faked out
to the upside we're looking for about 10
pips into the fake out to the upside and
then a reversal of about 15 so it'll
come back down to there we'll get a nice
little shape that looks like that and
then you're gonna get out of that trade
immediately and again it could go
further but we're just looking for that
pull up and then the retrace back to
basically
somewhat norm but a little bit more into
the other direction just a little bit
more now if that fast fast trading
doesn't suit your fancy I have two
methods that will go also quite quickly
but you can kind of trade them is at a
slower pace rather than just instantly
opening and closing your orders the
first one is again going to be a
reversal it's going to trend in a
direction after it's done this first
crazy wick pull back like this and then
it's gonna choose an actual direction to
go into so let's say that it did exactly
this faked out to the upside and then
broke back down here right what we're
gonna be planning to do is we're gonna
look for the pullback back to norm
before the actual trending market begins
after the NFP release because it's going
to have to pick a direction after all of
the major volatility has happened and
it's gonna have to retest this initial
zone so after it's picked that direction
what we're gonna do is we're gonna look
for it to slow and then we're gonna look
for the break back in the opposite
direction so if I just look for a line
here and we just draw kind of a line of
where the previous highs were or the
previous high here breaking down to low
you'll see that the reversal is gonna
happen generally right after we see that
break of the trend and then we start
reversing back so all you're gonna be
doing is you're going to be entering a
position after that reversal throw your
stop a little bit below the reversal
there just to make sure you keep any and
you possible wicks that might stop you
and then just target the very edge there
and you're gonna be getting on obviously
about a one to one hour trade you're
gonna get a equal risk to reward
generally with a trade like this most
likely you're gonna be able to get that
reversal all the way back to the top and
you're gonna quickly move your stop into
profit once it actually starts moving
because this is something again it's a
very quick but you're not doing
something just instantly like I said
before
now then the fourth option and this is
the one that makes most sense to me this
is what I do I don't like doing the
reversal I don't like doing the very
fast things I like to think I don't like
to just react very quickly that's
generally not what you should do some
guys they're amazing at it That's not me
some of you you're gonna try it you're
gonna be amazing at it I can tell
already some of you guys are nuts it's
cool so for those of you who are not
nuts
this is what I work with and this is
what I like to watch for on NFP and I
think we'll do a stream may be on NFP so
that you guys can see at some point here
too and and essentially we're gonna look
for that reversal like we were talking
about before and then that bounce off of
that level that initially broke out of
that same level that it broke out of and
then we can look for the little bit of
consolidation and the reversal on the
very small time frame back into that
trend and then we're just gonna jump
into that trend and follow that trend
for the rest of the day
and you can follow that all the way back
down to new highs and lows all the way
to whatever makes sense right so you're
gonna look for a level that means
something to you that's not what this
video is about this video is about just
the basic entry parameters of different
NFP strategies and those are the four
NFP strategies that doesn't go into a
ton of detail you need a ton of detail
on how to actually trade this isn't the
video this is for someone who's
specifically looking for an entry type
strategy or an explanation or an idea of
how they should be trading the NFP this
is not a video that's teaching you how
to trade use this in conjunction
junction with the knowledge that you
already have and I'm sure that some of
you are going to be able to make a great
profit with this just please please
please please make sure that you know
where you're gonna exit of the trade if
you are wrong because a lot of these
strategies they are relying on a high
risk scenario guys if you like that
content please make sure that you hit
the subscribe button hit that like hit
the notification bell because I'm just
dreaming most mondays Fridays and you
can jump in on the stream ask me all
sorts of questions call me call me names
make fun of me call me cute whatever you
want I love you guys all no matter what
you say to me and I'll see you guys next
time
[Music]